Wilton Historical Society Manuscript Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
- 3. People and families
  - Lambert, James - Correspondence, 1815 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 519)
  - Lambert, John James - Correspondence, 1813-1819; Includes letters to A. Betts and Sherman Betts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 520, 521)
  - Lambert, Samuel F. - School records, undated; Includes a school account book from Wilton Academy. See also WHI, Lambert papers. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 525)
  - Little family - Correspondence, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 547)
  - Little, Winnifred May - Correspondence with Archie M. Phinney, 1929-1936; Archie M. Phinney was a linguistic anthropologist and a Native American activist. The file includes love letters. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 548)
  - Lockwood family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 550)
  - Lockwood family - Papers, 1880-1890; Includes information on the wire factory. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 556)
  - Lockwood, Abigail - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 555)
  - Lockwood, Eliphalet - Papers, 1780 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 557)
  - Lockwood, G. W. - Financial records, 1858-1859 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 558)
  - Lockwood, John v. W. and H. Ruscoe - Lawsuit, 1855 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 560)
  - Lynch family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 564)
  - Lyon, Abigail - Estate records, 1851 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 565)
  - Marvin, Matthew - Papers, 1690-1823 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 570)
  - Mason, Helen Budd - Correspondence, undated; Includes correspondence with Wilton Historical Society. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 572)
  - McKeever, Archibald - Estate records, 1822 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 573)
  - Mead family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 574)
  - Mead, Thaddeus - Estate records, 1832 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 575)
  - Merwin, Samuel - Correspondence, 1837; Includes letter to Samuel and Alice Hitchcock, and Christmas card. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 590)
  - Middlebrook, Caroline - Legal documents, 1830; Includes a power of attorney. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 599)
  - Middlebrook, Charles - Correspondence, undated; Includes letters to James Middlebrook. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 600)
  - Middlebrook, Edward and Hannah - Financial records, 1835; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 605)
  - Middlebrook, George - Address book, 1906-1908 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 612)
  - Middlebrook, George - Correspondence and estate records, 1847-1852; Includes an estate list and letters to and regarding his son Sam. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 610)
  - Middlebrook, Henry - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 615)
  - Middlebrook, Jonathan - Estate records, 1781-1831 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 630, 632, 634)
  - Middlebrook, Sarah - Estate and financial records, 1838-1867; Includes an inventory, ledger, and report card. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 640)
  - Middlebrook, Sarah II - Papers, 1874; See also Diaries and Photographs. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 641)
  - Miller family - Papers, 1890-1900; Includes Cannon Stock and Dairy Farm papers. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 645)
  - Morehouse family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 651)
  - Morgan family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 652)
  - Morgan, William - Estate records, 1833 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 653, 654)
  - Nash, Hannah - Financial records, 1835-1841 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 656)
  - Nichols family - Papers, undated; See also Bethel. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 659)
  - Ogden family - Papers, 1942-1948 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 670)
  - Ogden, Adele - Financial records, 1911; Includes stock certificates. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 684a)
  - Ogden, Adele - Literary works, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 684b)
  - Ogden, Charles Jones - Correspondence, 1911 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 686)
  - Ogden, Charles Jones - School records, 1897 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 685)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Correspondence, 1936-1970 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 690, 694, 700)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Correspondence with Mary L. King, 1970-1971 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 692)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Correspondence with the Carlisle, Pennsylvania Historical Society, 1960-1961 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 696)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Correspondence with Virginia Bepler, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 701)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Literary scripts, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 712)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 703)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Poetry, 1955-1969 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 704, 705, 706, 707)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Review of old account book and soldiers pensions, 1946; "Review of old account book and soldiers pensions in the year 1790, written and read by Mr. F. Clerc Ogden at Wilton Historical Society meeting of June 8, 1946." (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-6)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Statue "The Little General", 1971 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 709)
  - Ogden, F. Clerc - Travel to Vermont, 1952; Journal of a cruise to Vermont. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 702)
  - Ogden, George - Poetry and correspondence, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 720)
  - Ogden, Rev. David - Diaries, 1844; The diaries were written in Europe. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 688)
  - Ogden, Rev. David - Travel, 1844 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 689)
  - Olmstead family - Financial records, 1844-1876; Includes miscellaneous receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 721, 722)
  - Olmstead family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 723)
  - Olmstead family - Papers relating to the Old Well District, 1803 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 724)
  - Olmstead, Alden - Legal documents, 1815; Includes his will. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 725)
  - Olmstead, Edward - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 726)
  - Olmstead, Harrison - Papers, 1833-1849 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 727)
  - Olmstead, Harrison - Papers, 1849-1855 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 728)
  - Olmstead, Hawley - Correspondence, 1817-1861 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 730, 731, 732)
  - Olmstead, Hawley - Financial records, 1852-1855; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 734)
  - Olmstead, Hawley - Legal documents, 1827-1856 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 733)
  - Olmstead, Hawley - School records, 1828-1839; Includes school publications. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 735)
  - Olmstead, James - Papers, 1822 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 737)
  - Olmstead, John - Estate records, 1869 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 742)
  - Olmstead, Marian - Newspaper clippings, 1890-1917; The clippings are in a scrapbook. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 743b)
  - Olmstead, Marian - Papers, 1885 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 743a)
  - Olmstead, Myrtle (Taylor) - Correspondence, 1918-1954 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 952, 953, 954a, 954b)
  - Olmstead, Nathan - Estate records, undated; Includes a map. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 744)
  - Olmstead, Rufus - Financial records, 1823-1897; Includes miscellaneous receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 745, 746, 747)
  - Olmstead, Sgt. Samuel - Estate and financial records and legal documents, 1863; Includes receipts, estate inventory, and will. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 749)
  - Olmstead, Sgt. Samuel - Military records, 1799-1804; Includes military commission and discharge papers. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 748)
  - Olmstead, Sgt. Samuel - Wedding and correspondence, undated; Includes social invitations. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 750)
  - Pardee family - Artwork, undated; This is an original, by "Angie." (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 751b)
  - Pardee family - Correspondence, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 751c)
  - Pardee family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 751a, 751d)
  - Post, Angeline - Correspondence, 1922-1951; The correspondence is on the topic of teaching. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 752a)
  - Post, Angeline - Student correspondence, 1950-1969 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 752aa, 752b, 752c, 752d)
  - Post, Angeline - Student poetry, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 752e)
  - Post, Angeline - Washington Post papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 752f)
  - Proctor, Gifford - Correspondence, 1936-1937; Includes correspondence with father A. Phimister Proctor and mother Margaret "Mody" Proctor. See also copies in Books 816.52 Proctor. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 758)
  - Raymond, Asahel - Estate records, 1782 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 770)
  - Raymond, Clapp - Papers, undated; Includes his research notes. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 771)
  - Raymond, Clarissa - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 772)
  - Raymond, Lewis - Papers, 1841-1880 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 773)
  - Reed, Matthew - Correspondence, 1846-1848; The correspondence is from April 1846 through January 1848. Matthew Reed, Jr., was a tanner in Norwalk. Matthew Reed, Sr., was writing from New York giving advice on business, farming, family, and miscellaneous other topics. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 776, 777, 778, 779)
  - Resseguie, Abijah - Apprenticeship and correspondence, 1838; Includes a letter from John Kortright and information on apprenticeship. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 780a)
  - Reynolds family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 779b)
  - Richards, Charles L. - Legal documents, 1877; Includes his will. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 780b)
  - Richards, Jane P. - Estate records, undated; Includes an inventory of stocks. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 780c)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - "Happenings in Hartford", undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781c)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - Certificates and awards, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781a)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - Correspondence, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781b)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - Personal papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781d)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - Politics, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781e)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - Speeches, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781f)
  - Rock, Isabel and Arthur - Wilton Women's Republican Club, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781g)
  - Rockwell, Clapp - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 781h)
  - Rockwell, Frank - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 782a)
  - Rockwell, Thomas - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 782c)
  - Rockwell, William - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 782b)
  - Rusco, Jehiel - Estate records, 1870; Includes a property list. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 783a)
  - Ruscoe family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 783b)
  - Russell, Mary and Peter - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 783c)
  - Sackmann family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 784)
  - Sanford, Samuel - Estate records, 1834 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 798a)
  - Schenck family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 798b)
  - Scott family - Papers, 1785-1883 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 800)
  - Scott, Ann E. - Papers, 1862 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 810)
  - Scott, Hanford - Correspondence, 1861-1887 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 820)
  - Scott, Hanford - Financial records, 1861-1887; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 825)
  - Scott, Hannah - Papers, 1851-1879 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 830)
  - Scott, John - Correspondence, 1832-1847; Includes correspondence with the Smith family. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 840)
  - Scott, John - Estate records, 1851-1853 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 845)
  - Scott, Samuel - Correspondence, 1832-1862; Includes correspondence with the Gilbert family. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 850, 852, 860)
  - Scott, Samuel - Estate records, 1861 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 864)
  - Scott, Samuel - Financial records, 1834-1848; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 862)
  - Scott, Samuel - Legal documents, 1837-1878; Includes a power of attorney. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 866)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Abraham Olmstead v. William Osborn - Lawsuit, 1842-1843 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 890)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Attachments and summons, 1826-1852 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 882)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Connecticut vs. Fowler Sellect - Lawsuit, 1846 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 894)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Financial records, 1830-1854; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 892)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - John Keeler v. George Alden - Lawsuit, 1831 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 884)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Land transfers, 1835-1853 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 886)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Miscellaneous cases, 1817-1856 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 870, 880)
  - Scott, Samuel (Justice of the Peace) - Nathan Leach, v. Charles Sturges - Lawsuit, 1846 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 888)
  - Scott, William - Property records, 1812; Includes a lease. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 896)
  - Seymour family - Correspondence, undated; Includes invitations and announcements. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 897c)
  - Seymour family - Financial records and miscellaneous papers, undated; Includes receipts. See also Oversized Manuscripts list. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 904)
  - Seymour family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 902a, 902b)
  - Seymour, Artemsia and LeGrand - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 897a)
  - Seymour, Clinton - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 897b)
  - Seymour, Jane Elizabeth - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 898a)
  - Seymour, Jared - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 899)
  - Seymour, John - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 901a)
  - Seymour, LeGrand - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 901b)
  - Sherwood, Reuben H. - Papers, 1867-1946; He was a Civil War soldier. Includes a Testimonial of Honor. (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-7)
  - Shoemaker family - Correspondence, 1857 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 905)
  - Sloan, Alexander - Property records, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 906)
  - Smith, Ezra - Estate records, 1860 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 907a)
  - Smith, Jane (Middlebrook) - Correspondence, 1865; Includes a letter to James Middlebrook. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 620)
  - St. John, Bela - Estate records, 1830-1835 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 786)
  - St. John, Col. Stephen - Property records, 18th century (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 789c)
  - St. John, James - Estate records, 1830-1835 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 787, 788a)
  - St. John, James - Financial records, 1796-1817 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 788b)
  - St. John, John M. - Papers, 1900; Includes a certificate. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 789a)
  - St. John, Noah - Papers, 1859; Includes an appointment of overseer. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 789b)
  - Steichen, Kate - Correspondence, 1954-1984; Includes correspondence with Vincent Price, Mrs. E. B. (Katherine) White, general correspondence, and letters on the topics of dowsing and Eliot Clark. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 908a, 908b, 908c, 908d, 908e)
  - Sterling family - Financial records and miscellaneous papers, 1857; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 909a)
  - Sterling family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 908g)
  - Sturges family - Correspondence, undated; Includes family greeting cards. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 931)
  - Sturges family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 930b)
  - Sturges, Aaron - Correspondence, undated; Includes correspondence with L. Scott. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 910)
  - Sturges, Benjamin - Military records, undated; Includes information on his military commission and work as a notary public. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 915)
  - Sturges, Daniel - Legal documents, 1799; Includes a quit claim deed. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 916)
  - Sturges, Dr. Fred - Correspondence, undated; Includes correspondence with Helen Elizabeth Sturges (his niece). (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 932)
  - Sturges, Dr. Fred - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers, 1851-1899; Includes correspondence with his family. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 933)
  - Sturges, Elias - Estate records, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 917)
  - Sturges, Eliphalet - Legal documents, 1868; Includes a copy of his will. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 918)
  - Sturges, Elizabeth - Correspondence, 1838-1858; Includes correspondence with family members. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 919)
  - Sturges, Eratus - Papers, 1834-1843 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 920)
  - Sturges, Ezekiel - Estate administration records, 1853-1865; Includes Ezekiel Sturges's papers as administrator of the estates of Catherine Adams, Lucy Betts, and Elisha Lyman. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 930a)
  - Sturges, Ezekiel - Papers, 1815-1837 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 925)
  - Sturges, Frederick Sherman - Papers, 1932 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 934)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - "Amazing Achievements", 1967 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 935)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers, 1904-1907 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 940)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Correspondence from England, 1914 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 937)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Correspondence with her brothers in England, 1914 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 942)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Correspondence with her sister, Florence Sturges Coley, 1903-1937 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 939)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Correspondence with her Uncle Arthur, 1914-1915 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 938)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Correspondence, memorial service, and miscellaneous papers, 1914-1970 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 936)
  - Sturges, Helen Elizabeth - Newspaper, 1898; The newspaper was edited by H. E. Sturges. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 941)
  - Sturges, Isaac - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 946)
  - Sturges, John Burr - Papers, 1857 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 947)
  - Sturges, Samuel B. - Correspondence, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 948c)
  - Sturges, Samuel B. - Estate records, 1872 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 948b)
  - Sturges, Samuel B. - Financial records, 1842-1855; Includes checks and receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 948a)
  - Sturges, William - Papers, 1836 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 949a)
  - Sutton, Polly - Papers, 1888 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 949b)
  - Taylor, Charles - Financial records, 1803-1823 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 950)
  - Taylor, James - Death records of an undertaker, 1847-1896; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1141)
  - Taylor, Levy - Correspondence, 1802; Includes correspondence with Betts and Raymond. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 951)
  - Telford, D. D. - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 955)
  - Terrel, Daniel - Legal documents, 1830; Includes a lease. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 957)
  - Trowbridge family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1048b)
  - Turner, Dr. Edward - Papers, 1860-1861; Includes information on quarry and asylum time book. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1049)
  - Tuttle, Mildred (Moran) - Financial records, 1930; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1050)
  - Van Zandt family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 545)
  - Wakeman, Sarah - Correspondence, financial records, and miscellaneous, 1877-1905; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1150)
  - Wells family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1165)
  - Westcott, Clarence - School records, 1855; Includes a school account book from Wilton Academy. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1170)
  - Whitlock family - Correspondence, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1190)
  - Whitlock family - Financial records, 1924-1941; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1195)
  - Whitlock family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1192)
  - Whitlock, A. - Financial records, 1875-1883; Includes record of a loan payment. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1200)
  - Whitlock, Abel - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1205)
  - Whitlock, Anna Belle - Financial records, 1921-1953; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1210)
  - Whitlock, Augustus - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1215)
  - Whitlock, Charles - Financial records, 1919-1941; Includes receipts (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1220)
  - Whitlock, Emily - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1225)
  - Whitlock, John I, and John Whitlock, III - Estate records and legal documents, 1825; Includes a will and inventory. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1230)
  - Whitlock, Oliver - Estate records, 1658-1733 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1235)
  - Whitlock, Rachel - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1240)
  - Whittlesey family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1250)
  - Willard family - Papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1260)
  - Williams, Henry - Financial records, 1846; Includes a daybook. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1270)
  - Wilson family - Legal documents, 1667-1697; Includes copies of wills. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1280)
  - Winton, Andrew Lincoln - Papers, 1864-1946 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1300)
  - Winton, Kate - Scientific drawings, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1310)
  - Wittwell, Leslie - Diary, 1918-1919; Diary covers World War One. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1350)
- Betts-Raymond Store papers
  - Betts-Raymond store, 1780-1878 (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 2, 4)
  - Betts-Raymond store - Correspondence, 1780-1878 (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 154)
  - Betts-Raymond store - Financial records (bills and payments), 1802-1825 (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 10, 12, 14, 16, 18, 20, 22, 24, 26, 28, 30, 36, 38, 40, 42, 44, 46, 48, 50, 52, 54, 56, 58)
  - Betts-Raymond store - Financial records (miscellaneous bills), undated (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 152)
  - Betts-Raymond store - Financial records (orders and receipts), 1802-1825 (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 100, 102, 104, 106, 108, 110, 112, 114, 116, 118, 120, 122, 124, 126, 128, 130, 132, 134, 136, 138, 140, 142, 144, 146, 148)
  - Betts-Raymond store - Inventories, undated (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 150)
  - Betts-Raymond store - Miscellaneous inventories, undated (Box Cabinet: 11, Folder 156)
- David Hermon Van Hoosear papers
  - Bailey, James H. - "Genealogical records compiled from vol. 19 of the land records of the town of Norwalk", 1893; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. Contents were omitted from Hall's Norwalk. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1086)
  - Cemetery - Bedford, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1054)
  - Cemetery - Newtown, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1082)
  - Cemetery - Old cemeteries in Westport, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. Cemeteries included are Adams, Cedar Point, Compo, Greens Farms, Cranberry Plain, Platt, Willowbrook, and Evergreen. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1126, 1128)
  - Cemetery - Old Fairfield - Inscriptions on headstones, 1712-1770; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1060)
  - Cemetery - Private in New Canaan - Inscriptions of headstones, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1074)
  - Cemetery - Silvermine Upper in Norwalk, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1094)
  - Cemetery - St. Paul's in Norwalk, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1095)
  - Cemetery - Whitney Hill (Mill Hill) in Norwalk, 1795-1808; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1096)
  - Cemetery - Witch Lane in Norwalk, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1098)
  - Church - Congregational - Records; and St. John's Episcopal in Stamford - Marriages, 1758; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. Records date from March 28, 1758. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1110)
  - Church - Congregational in New Canaan - Baptisms, 1733; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. Records date from June 23, 1733. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1078)